Graeme Thornber

Mobile: +6421 0292 4529

E-mail: gdthornber@gmail.com **Website:** www.graemethornber.com

Profile

Full-Stack Open-Source Web Developer with 12 solid years experience building and maintaining modern web applications in Auckland, Wellington and Bonn, Germany.

I've worked with some of New Zealand's top digital and design agencies on a range of projects with local and global clients. I write extensible, readable, reusable code in a variety of open-source languages, using a flexible array of Javascript and PHP-based CMS frameworks.

I'm also a musician and actor, playing mainly guitar and anything else with strings including piano. In 2018 I acted with Whitianga's Offbeat Theatre in my 5th play, and co-founded a local improv theatre group.

Education

2005 - 2006 Natcoll (Auckland, New Zealand)

Diploma in Web Development

1992 – 1996 Howick College (Auckland, New Zealand)

English, Computer Studies, Drama, Music, Japanese

Employment History

2017 - 2018 Senior Remote Developer DNA (Auckland, NZ) <u>www.dna.co.nz</u>

Working remotely in an Agile environment for clients mainly in the public sector on Silverstripe's CWP platform: www.business.govt.nz, www.fma.govt.nz, www.gccrs.govt.nz, www.greatjourneysofnz.co.nz, www.immigration.govt.nz, www.pikeriverrecovery.govt.nz, www.rideforever.co.nz, www.sportnz.org.nz, www.tenancy.govt.nz

2016

Lead Developer

Spitfire: The Digital Agency (Auckland, NZ) www.spitfire.co.nz

Managing contractors and working across many projects and platforms, mainly with Concrete5 CMS.

www.roche.co.nz, www.cancerinfo.co.nz, www.chelsea.co.nz

2014 - 2015

Freelance Developer (Auckland, NZ) www.graemethornber.com

Working with a variety of technology stacks for digital agencies including:

<u>Colenso BBDO, RAPP (DDB), Image Center Group, iDesignMedia, Insight Creative, J.</u>
Walter Thompson, <u>Satellite Media, Touchcast</u>

2011 - 2013

Senior PHP Developer

Scopevisio AG (Bonn, Germany) - www.scopevisio.com

Building and maintaining the company's website in Drupal using Web Services with REST, SOAP, JSON and XML while also gaining an advanced knowledge of SEO.

www.scopevisio.com, www.centerdevice.de

2010 - 2011

Lead Developer / Project Manager

+The Church+ (Wellington, NZ) - www.thechurch.co.nz

Building custom Wordpress themes and plugins for local and international clients, I took sole ownership of many projects - from initial scoping and architecture to building, deploying and maintaining bespoke content-management driven web applications.

Ngati Toa Rangatira, NZSO, RJ's Licorice, Toi Whakaari, Toyota

2008 - 2010

Front End Developer

Solutionists (Auckland, NZ) - <u>www.solutionists.co.nz</u>

During my time at Solutionists I worked on over 100 projects: from building HTML email templates and brochure campaigns to full corporate E-Commerce solutions for clients such as:.

Barkers, Huffer, Ministry of Health, Overland Footwear, Random House

2007 - 2008

Freelance Developer (Auckland, NZ) - www.graemethornber.com

After completing my Diploma in 2006 I made the transition from hospitality to the web industry contracting for clients in Auckland including

Zest Media and Brown Paper Bag.

1997 - 2006

Waiter, Bartender, Restaurant Supervisor, Event Manager

Bars, Restaurant and Events in Auckland:

Horse & Trap (Mt Eden), Kermadec (Viaduct), Kings Arms (Newton), Portofino (Mission Bay), Vivace (High St), White Horse Inn (Pakuranga) and London:

The Feathers (Westminster), The Jolly Gardeners (Putney)

Technical Skills

Javascript: jQuery, ES6, Node.js, Expres, ReactJS, AngularJS, Ember

CSS3: SASS, LESS, Stylus, Flexbox, Compass, Normalize, PostCSS

HTML5:, Bootstrap, Foundation, Pure, Twig, Mustache, Smarty

PHP7: OOP, MVC, PSR-2, Laravel, Symfony, Zend, Codelgniter, CakepHp

Data: MySQL, XML, JSON, CSV, MongoDB, Mongoose, Firebase, HeidiSQL

CMS: Silverstripe, Wordpress, Drupal, Bolt, Concrete5, Joomla, Typo3

Agile & team tools: Git, Slack, Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket, Basecamp, Trello

Accessibility: WCAG2, WAI-ARIA, WebAIM, WAVE, Axe, NVDA, VoiceOver

CLI tools: NPM, Composer, Gulp, Webpack, Yarn, Babel, Grunt, Bower

E-Commerce: Magento, Zen Cart, Shopify, WooCommerce, BigCommerce

Design tools: Sketch, InVision, Photoshop, Fireworks, InDesign, Illustrator

Animation: CSS Transitions & Keyframes, HTML5 Canvas, Flash Actionscript

Web Services: AJAX, REST, cURL, AWS, Rackspace, SOAP, PEAR

Google: Maps API, YouTube API, Search Console, Analytics, Adwords

E-mail / PDF: Campaign Monitor, MailChimp, Litmus, Mandrill, CleverReach

Server setup: Apache, Linux, DigitalOcean, MAMP, XAMPP, Plesk, cPanel

DevOps: Capistrano, Jenkins, Beam, Beanstalk, Raygun, Graylog

IDEs: Atom, Sublime Text, Xcode, PhpStorm, Notepad++, NetBeans, Eclipse

As well as the above I also have a very basic knowledge of:

ASP.NET, C, C#, Java, Go, Python, Ruby, Swift

I'm currently learning:

Vue.js, TypeScript, Postgres, PostGIS and geospatial data mapping

Other skills:

- Mastery of English with excellent formal and creative writing skills
- I'm involved in the theatre and run a bi-weekly improv group
- Over 25 years experience playing guitar and other instruments
- Can speak German and read / write Japanese
- Wit, personality and a sense of humour

Examples of my work can be found on my website at: www.graemethornber.com